<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Citizen Science on SURPASS2</title>
    <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/categories/citizen-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Citizen Science on SURPASS2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/categories/citizen-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Science and Pollinators of South America</title>
      <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/blog/citizenscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/blog/citizenscience/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The book Citizen Science and Pollinators of South America provides us, through a clear, direct and accessible language, a useful and enjoyable reading. It is an original work that brings together for the first time, in a single volume, knowledge about pollinators and successful experiences of citizen science projects in South America. in South America, focusing on this biodiversity.&amp;rdquo; Blandina Felipe Viana, Universidade Federal da Bahia
The digital version of this book is freely available - Spanish (PDF/epub) or Portuguese (PDF)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoMS overseas</title>
      <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/blog/poms_ff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/blog/poms_ff/</guid>
      <description>Counting pollinators In the frame of the NERC-funded project SURPASS2 (Safeguarding pollination services in a changing world: theory into practice) that gathers researchers of UK, Argentina, Brazil, and Chile, we implemented for the first time the FIT count methodology in Chile.
Through a collaboration with the local EXPLORA project from La Araucanía Region, in southern Chile, we adapted the pollinator monitoring scheme developed in the UK for South America. In this opportunity, children from elementary schools of the Araucanía region.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
