<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on SURPASS2</title>
    <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on SURPASS2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insect Pollinator Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp1_monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp1_monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring the status and trends of pollinators and pollination services Evidence of large-scale declines in pollinators exists in North America and Europe, yet relatively little is known of their status and trends in South America. A robust monitoring approach is critical to increase the evidence base for understanding threats to animal pollinators and underpin policies for their sustainable management and conservation.
In the UK, CEH has led the development of a National Pollinator and Pollination Monitoring Framework, which is currently implementing the UK Pollinator Monitoring Scheme using a combination of volunteer citizen science and professionally led surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop Pollination &amp; Invasive Species</title>
      <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp2_experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp2_experiment/</guid>
      <description>Assess the impacts of landscape intensification and context on pollinator abundance and behaviour Agricultural expansion and intensification have been linked with losses of pollinators and pollination, and although multiple pressures interact, habitat clearance and deterioration are considered the most important drivers of these effects. Effective monitoring of populations and their impact on pollination services is thus a crucial part of validating the cost of such management. In WP2 of the SURPASS project, we are looking at how wild insects, principally bees, provide key pollination services to a range of crops in Argentina, Brazil and Chile, and how this is affected by surrounding landscape factors that help support these wild pollinators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Landcover Mapping</title>
      <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp3_landcover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp3_landcover/</guid>
      <description>Mapping Land Cover and Pollination Demand Remote sensing products, ground information and pollination service models will be used to develop land cover maps capable of informing about the distribution of pollination demand. When coupled with functional trait and interaction network models, these maps will help us quantify the demand in pollination services across landscapes and better predict and manage stocks and benefits available. These tools will also help us identify potential mismatches between high demand and low supply of pollination services to allow targeting of interventions (mitigation &amp;amp; conservation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecosystem Services</title>
      <link>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp4_modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://retoschmucki.github.io/surpass2web/portfolio/wp4_modelling/</guid>
      <description>Modelling Pollination Services and Insect Populations Managed and wild bees provide important pollination services for many crops. While the demand for pollination has been increasing, bee abundances have been declining in many areas.
It is important to study how agricultural landscapes affect bee populations and how bees in turn improve the pollination of crops. Understanding these processes in more detail will help us create a win-win situation for farmers and bees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
